Guide to the Wilfrid S. Sellars Papers, 1899-1990 ASP.1991.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Library, V.
  - Annotated Books, dates; 1.
    - Flew, Anthony. Essays on Logic and Language, edited with an introduction. Philosophical Library, 1951 (Box 182, Item 651)
    - Werkmeister, W.H. A History of Philosophical Ideas in America. The Ronald Press Company, 1949 (Box 182, Item 652)
    - McMullin, Ernan. The Concept of Matter, edited. University of Notre Dame Press, 1963 (Box 182, Item 653)
    - Fraasen, Bas C. Van. The Scientific Image. Clarendon Press, 1980 (Box 182, Item 654)
    - Castell, Alburey. An Introduction to Modern Philosophy, in six philosophical problems. The Macmillan Company, 1943 (Box 182, Item 655)
    - Schilpp, Paul Arthur. The Philosophy of G.E. Moore, edited. Northwestern University, 1942 (Box 182, Item 656)
    - Schilpp, Paul Arthur. The Philosophy of Alfred North Whitehead, edited. Northwestern University, 1941 (Box 182, Item 657)
    - Schilpp, Paul Arthur. The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap, edited. Open Court, 1963 (Box 182, Item 658)
    - Pitcher, George. Wittgenstein, The Philosophical Investigations, edited. Anchor Books, Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1966 (Box 182, Item 659)
    - Braithwaite, R.B. An Empiricist's View on the Nature of Religious Belief. Cambridge at the University Press, 1955 (Box 182, Item 660)
    - Potter, Vincent G. Charles S. Peirce, On Norms & Ideals. The University of Massachusetts Press, 1967 (Box 182, Item 661)
    - Lauer, Quentin. A Reading of Hegel's Phenomenology of Spirit. Fordham University Press, 1976 (Box 182, Item 662)
    - Madden, Edward H. Chauncey Wright and the Foundations of Pragmatism. University of Washington Press, 1963 (Box 182, Item 663)
    - Wick, Warner Arms. Metaphysics and the New Logic. The University of Chicago Press, 1942 (Box 182, Item 664)
    - Britton, Karl. John Stuart Mill. Penguin Books, 1953 (Box 182, Item 665)
    - Laird, John. Recent Philosophy. Thornton Butterworth Ltd, 1936 (Box 182, Item 666)
    - McRae, Robert. Leibniz: Perception, Apperception, and Thought. University of Toronto Press, 1976 (Box 182, Item 667)
    - Sawyer, W.W. Mathematician's Delight. Penguin Books, 1943 (Box 182, Item 668)
    - Brown, Robert. Explanation in Social Science. Routledge & Kegan Paul, 1963 (Box 182, Item 669)
    - Grunbaum, Adolf. Modern Science and Zeno's Paradoxes. Wesleyan University Press, 1967 (Box 182, Item 670)
    - Carnap, Rudolf. Meaning and Necessity, A Study in Semantics and Modal Logic. The University of Chicago Press, 1947 (Box 182, Item 671)
    - Feyerabend, Paul K. and Grover Maxwell. Mind, Matter, and Method, Essays in Philosophy of Science in Honor of Herbert Feigl, edited. University of Minnesota Press, 1966 (Box 182, Item 672)
    - Brodbeck, May. Readings in the Philosophy of the Social Sciences, edited. The Macmillan Company, 1949 (Box 182, Item 673)
    - Feigl, Herbert and May Brodbeck. Readings in the Philosophy of Science, edited. The Macmillan Company, 1968 (Box 182, Item 674)
    - Pap, Arthur. Semantics and Necessary Truth, An Inquiry into the Foundations of Analytic Philosophy. Yale University Press, 1958 (Box 182, Item 675)
    - Pap, Arthur. Elements of Analytic Philosophy. The Macmillan Company, 1949 (Box 182, Item 676)
    - Lorenzen, Paul. Normative Logic and Ethics. Bibliographisches Institut, Hochschultaschenbucher-Verlag, 1969 (Box 182, Item 677)
    - Randall, John Herman, Jr. The Making of the Modern Mind, revised edition, A Survey of the Intellectual Background of the Present Age. Houghton Mifflin Company, 1940 (Box 182, Item 678)
    - Northrop, F.S.C. Science and First Principles. The Macmillan Company, 1931 (Box 182, Item 679)
    - Wiener, Philip P. Readings in Philosophy of Science, Introduction to the Foundations and Cultural Aspects of the Sciences, arranged and edited. Charles Scribner's Sons, 1953 (Box 182, Item 680)
    - Pearson, Karl. Clifford, William Kingdon: The Common Sense of the Exact Sciences, edited and with a preface, newly edited and with an introduction. Alfred A. Knopf, 1946 (Box 182, Item 681)
    - Geach, Peter and Max Black. Translations from the Philosophical Writings of Gottlob Frege, edited. Philosophical Library, 1952 (Box 182, Item 682)
    - Wiener, Norbert. Cybernetics, or Control and Communication in the Animal and the Machine. The Technology Press, 1948 (Box 182, Item 683)
    - Chisholm, Roderick M. Theory of Knowledge, second edition. Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1977 (Box 182, Item 684)
    - Sobocinski, Boleslaw. An Investigation of Protothetic. Editions de L'Institut D'Etudes Polonaises en Belgique, 1949 (Box 182, Item 685)
    - McKeon, Richard. Selections from Medieval Philosophers, II, Roger Bacon to William of Ockham, edited and translated, with introductory notes and glossary. Charles Scribner's Sons, 1930 (Box 182, Item 686)
    - Psychical Research, Ethics and Logic, The Symposia Readd at the Joint Session of The Aristotelian Society and the Mind Association at Bristol, July 7th-9th, 1950. Harrison and Sons, Ltd. (Box 182, Item 687)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid. Science and Metaphysics, Variations on Kantian Themes. Routledge & Kegan Paul, 1967 (Box 182, Item 688)
    - Vaihinger, H., Dr. Commentar zu Kants Kritik der ReinenVernunft, zum hundertjahrigen jubilaum derselben, herausgegeben. Verlag von W. Spemann, 1881 (Box 182, Item 689)
    - Ruytinx, Jacques. La Problematique Philosophique de L'Unite de la Science, etude critique. Societe d'Edition "Les Belles Lettres", 1962 (Box 182, Item 690)
    - Strawson, P.F. Logico-Linguistic Papers. Methuen & Co Ltd, 1971 (Box 182, Item 691)
    - Strawson, P.F. Philosophical Logic, edited. Oxford University Press, 1967 (Box 182, Item 692)
    - Hall, H.S. and S.R. Knight. Higher Algebra, A Sequel to Elementary Algebra for Schools, Fourth Edition. Macmillan and Co., Limited, 1929 (Box 182, Item 693)
    - Korner, Stephan. The Philosophy of Mathematics, An Introductory Essay. Hutchinson University Library, 1960 (Box 182, Item 694)
    - Christensen, Niels Egmont. On the Nature of Meanings, A Philosophical Analysis. Munksgaard, 1961 (Box 182, Item 695)
    - Tarski, Alfred. Introduction to Logic, and to the Methodology of Deductive Sciences. Oxford University Press, 1946 (Box 182, Item 696)
    - Fisk, Milton. A Modern Formal Logic. Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1964 (Box 182, Item 697)
    - Quine, Willard Van Orman. Mathematical Logic. W.W. Norton & Company, Inc., 1940 (Box 182, Item 698)
    - Johnson, W.E. Logic, Part III, The Logical Foundations of Science. Cambridge at the University Press, 1924 (Box 182, Item 699)
    - Ziff, Paul. Semantic Analysis. Cornell University Press, 1960 (Box 182, Item 700)
    - Newman, James R. The World of Mathematics, A small library of the literature of mathematics from A'h-mose the Scribe to Albert Einstein, presented with commentaries and notes. Simon and Schuster, 1956 (Box 182, Item 701)
    - Jowett, B. The Dialogues of Plato, translated into English, with an introduction by Professor Raphael Demos, Volume Two. Random House, 1937 (Box 182, Item 702)
    - Dem Schopfer der Mengenlehre Herrn Georg Cantor in Dankbarer Verehrung Gewidmet. N.p. (Box 182, Item 703)
    - Chapman, Frank Miller and Paul Henle. The Fundamentals of Logic. Charles Scribner's Sons, 1933 (Box 182, Item 704)
    - Koch, Anton F. Vernunft und Sinnlichkeit im Praktischen Denken, Eine Sprachbehavioristische Rekonstruktion Kantischer Theoreme Gegen Sellars. Konigshausen & Neumann, 1980 (Box 182, Item 705)
    - Lewis, Clarence Irving and Cooper Harold Langford. Symbolic Logic. The Century Co., 1932 (Box 182, Item 706)
    - Salmon, Wesley C. Zeno's Paradoxes, edited. The Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1970 (Box 182, Item 707)
    - Aune, Bruce. Rationalism, Empiricism, and Pragmatism, An Introduction. Random House, 1970 (Box 182, Item 708)
    - Robinson, Richard. The Province of Logic, An Interpretation of Certain Parts of Cook Wilson's "Statement and Inference". George Routledge & Sons, Ltd., 1931 (Box 182, Item 709)
    - Ferre, Frederick. Language, Logic, and God. Harper Torchbooks, Harper & Row, 1961 (Box 182, Item 710)
    - Moody, Ernest A. Truth and Consequence in Medieval Logic. North-Holland Publishing Company, 1953 (Box 182, Item 711)
    - Blanshard, Brand. Reason and Belief. Yale University Press, 1975 (Box 182, Item 712)
    - Blanshard, Brand. The Nature of Thought, Volume One. George Allen & Unwin Ltd, 1939 (Box 182, Item 713)
    - Blanshard, Brand. The Nature of Thought, Volume Two. George Allen & Unwin Ltd, 1939 (Box 182, Item 714)
    - Ayer, A.J. Logical Positivism, edited. The Free Press, 1959 (Box 182, Item 715)
    - Ayer, A.J. The Concept of a Person, and other essays. St Martin's Press Inc, 1963 (Box 182, Item 716)
    - Clark, Manning. A Short History of Australia. The New American Library, 1963 (Box 182, Item 717)
    - Fritz, Charles A., Jr. Bertrand Russell's Construction of the External World. Routledge & Kegan Paul Ltd, 1952 (Box 182, Item 718)
    - Fritz, Charles A., Jr. Bertrand Russell's Construction of the External World. The Humanities Press Inc, 1952 (Box 182, Item 719)
    - Russell, Bertrand. Human Knowledge, Its Scope and Limits. Simon and Schuster, 1948 (Box 182, Item 720)
    - Martin, R.M. Belief, Existence, and Meaning. New York University Press, 1969 (Box 182, Item 721)
    - Russell, Bertrand. My Philosophical Development, with an appendix, Russell's Philosophy, by Alan Wood. Simon and Schuster, 1959 (Box 182, Item 722)
    - Tomberlin, James E. Hector-Neri Castaneda, edited. D. Reidel Publishing Company, 1986 (Box 182, Item 723)
    - Ellis, Brian. Basic Concepts of Measurement. Cambridge at the University Press, 1966 (Box 182, Item 724)
    - Simpson, Thomas Moro. Formas logicas, realidad, y significado. Eudeba Editorial Universitaria de Buenos Aires, 1964 (Box 182, Item 725)
    - Whitehead, Alfred North and Bertrand Russell. Principia Mathematica to *56. Cambridge at the University Press, 1962 (Box 182, Item 726)
    - Russell, Bertrand. Mysticism and Logic. Doubleday Anchor Books, 1960 (Box 182, Item 727)
    - Bondi, Hermann. The Universe at Large. Anchor Books, Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1960 (Box 182, Item 728)
    - Russell, Bertrand. The Problems of Philosophy. Thornton Butterworth Limited, 1912 (Box 182, Item 729)
    - Gustafson, Donald F. Essays in Philosophical Psychology, edited. Anchor Books, Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1964 (Box 182, Item 730)
    - Borger, Robert and Frank Cioffi. Explanations in the Behavioural Sciences, edited. Cambridge University Press, 1975 (Box 182, Item 731)
    - Grunbaum, Adolf. Philosophical Problems of Time and Space, second, enlarged edition. D. Reidel Publishing Company, 1973 (Box 182, Item 732)
    - Myers, Gerald E. Self, Religion, and Metaphysics, essays in memory of James Bissett Pratt, edited. The Macmillan Company, 1961 (Box 182, Item 733)
    - Lovejoy, Arthur O. The Revolt Against Dualism, An Inquiry Concerning the Existence of Ideas. The Open Court Publishing Company, W.W. Norton & Company, Inc., 1930 (Box 182, Item 734)
    - Lean, Martin. Sense-Perception and Matter, A Critical Analysis of C.D. Broad's Theory of Perception. The Humanities Press Inc, 1953 (Box 182, Item 735)
    - Flew, Anthony and Alasdair Macintyre. New Essays in Philosophical Theology, edited. The Macmillan Company, 1955 (Box 182, Item 736)
    - Davidson, Donald and Patrick Suppes. Decision Making, an experimental approach, in collaboration with Sidney Siegel. Stanford University Press, 1957 (Box 182, Item 737)
    - Korner, Stephan. Experience and Theory, An Essay in the Philosophy of Science. Routledge & Kegan Paul, 1966 (Box 182, Item 738)
    - Black, M. Carnap, Rudolf: The Unity of Science, translated with an introduction. Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner & Co. Ltd, 1934 (Box 182, Item 739)
    - Martin, Seymour, et al. A History of Philosophy. F.S. Crofts & Co., 1941 (Box 182, Item 740)
    - Furth, Montgomery. Frege, Gottlob: The Basic Laws of Arithmetic, Exposition of the System, translated and edited, with an introduction. University of California Press, 1964 (Box 182, Item 741)
    - Reichenbach, Hans. Experience and Prediction, An Analysis of the Foundations and the Structure of Knowledge. University of Chicago Press, 1938 (Box 182, Item 742)
    - Castaneda, Hector-Neri. Intentionality, Minds, and Perception, Discussions on Contemporary Philosophy, A Symposium, compiled with an introduction. Wayne State University Press, 1967 (Box 182, Item 743)
    - Lambert, Karel. The Logical Way of Doing Things, edited. Yale University Press, 1969 (Box 182, Item 744)
    - Colodny, Robert G. Mind and Cosmos, Essays in Contemporary Science and Philosophy, edited. University of Pittsburgh Press, 1966 (Box 182, Item 745)
    - Fillmore, Charles J. and D. Terence Langendoen. Studies in Linguistic Semantics, edited. Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1971 (Box 182, Item 746)
    - Whitrow, G.J. The Natural Philosophy of Time. Thomas Nelson and Sons Ltd, 1961 (Box 182, Item 747)
    - Colodny, Robert G. Beyond the Edge of Certainty, Essays in Contemporary Science and Philosophy, edited. Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1965 (Box 182, Item 748)
    - Paton, H.J. The Moral Law, or Kant's Groundwork of the Metaphysic of Morals, a new translation with analysis and notes. Hutchinson's University Library (Box 182, Item 749)
    - French, Peter A., et al. Contemporary Perspectives in the Philosophy of Language, edited. University of Minnesota Press, 1979 (Box 182, Item 750)
    - Vesey, Godfrey. Personal Identity, A Philosophical Analysis. Cornell University Press, 1974 (Box 182, Item 751)
    - Cairns, Dorion. Husserl, Edmund: Cartesian Meditations, An Introduction to Phenomenology, translated. Martinus Nijhoff, 1960 (Box 182, Item 752)
    - Hempel, Carl G. Philosophy of Natural Science. Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1966 (Box 182, Item 753)
    - Glymour, Clark. Theory and Evidence. Princeton University Press, 1980 (Box 182, Item 754)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell. Autocrat of the Breakfast Table, The. J.M. Dent & Co., 1906 (Box 182, Item 755)
    - Russell, Bertrand. Philosophy of Logical Atomism, The, Lectures delivered in 1918 and published as a series of articles by the Monist in the volumes for 1918 and 1919. Department of Philosophy, University of Minnesota (Box 182, Item 756)
    - Faber, Marvin. Phenomenology and Existence, Toward a Philosophy within Nature. Harper & Row, 1967 (Box 182, Item 757)
    - Peirce, Charles S.; [edited with an introduction an notes by Philip P. Wiener]. Values in a Universe of Chance, selected writings of… Stanford University Press, 1958 (Box 182, Item 758)
    - Peirce, Charles S.; [edited with an introduction and notes by Philip P. Wiener]. Values in a Universe of Chance, selected writings of… Doubleday Anchor Books, 1958 (Box 182, Item 759)
    - Copi, Irving M. Symbolic Logic. The Macmillan Company, 1954 (Box 182, Item 760)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid. Science and Metaphysics, Variations on Kantian Themes. Routledge & Kegan Paul, 1967 (Box 182, Item 761)
    - Bergson, Henri; [authorized translation by F.L. Pogson]. Time and Free Will, An Essay on the Immediate Data of Consciousness. George Allen & Unwin Ltd, 1910 (Box 182, Item 762)
    - Gram, M.S. and E.D. Klemke. Ontological Turn, The, Studies in the Philosophy of Gustav Bergmann. University of Iowa Press, 1974 (Box 182, Item 763)
    - Wittgenstein, Ludwig. Blue and Brown Books, The Preliminary Studies for the "Philosophical Investigations", Generally known as. Harper & Row, 1965 (Box 182, Item 764)
    - Tolstoy, Leo; [translated by Louise and Aylmer Maude]. War and Peace, a novel in three volumes, v.1 in hand. Oxford University Press (Box 182, Item 765)
    - Paton, H.J. Modern Predicament, The, a study in the philosophy of religion, based on the Gifford Lectures delivered in the University of St. Andrews. George Allen & Unwin Ltd, 1955 (Box 182, Item 766)
    - James, William. Will to Believe, The, and other essays in popular philosophy, and Human Immorality. Dover Publications, Inc., 1956 (Box 182, Item 767)
    - James, William. Principles of Psychology, The, V.1 in hand. Dover Publications, Inc., 1956 (Box 182, Item 768)
    - Reilly, Francis E. Charles Peirce's Theory of Scientific Method. Fordham University Press, 1970 (Box 182, Item 769)
    - McMullin, ed. Concept of Matter, The. University of Notre Dame Press, 1963 (Box 182, Item 770)
    - Hempel, Carl G. Aspects of Scientific Explanation and other essays in the Philosophy of Science. The Free Press, 1965 (Box 182, Item 771)
    - Kant, Immanuel. Critique of Pure Reason. St. Martin's Press, 1965 (Box 182, Item 772)
    - Peirce, Charles S.; [edited by Arthur W. Burks]. Collected Papers, V.8 (Reviews, Correspondence, and Bibliography) in hand. Harvard University Press, 1958 (Box 182, Item 773)
    - Machamer, Peter K. and Robert G. Turnbull, eds. Studies in Perception, Interrelations in the History of Philosophy and Science. Ohio State University Press, 1978 (Box 182, Item 774)
    - Mora, Jose Ferrater. Being and Death, an Outline of Integrationist Philosophy, Translated from the Spanish with Extensive Revisions by the author. University of California Press, 1965 (Box 182, Item 775)
    - Valery, Paul. Variete II, dix-septieme edition. Librairie Gallimard, Editions de la Nouvelle Revue Francaise, 1930 (Box 182, Item 776)
    - Robinson, John Mansley. Introduction to Early Greek Philosophy, An, The Chief Fragments and Ancient Testimony, with Connecting Commentary. Houghton Mifflin Company, 1968 (Box 182, Item 777)
    - Hughes, Robert. Fatal Shore, The. Vintage Books, 1988 (Box 182, Item 778)
    - Bougle, C.; [translated by Helen Stalker Sellars, with an introduction by Roy Wood Sellars]. Evolution of Values, The, Studies in Sociology with Special Applications to Teaching. Henry Holt and Company, 1926 (Box 182, Item 779)
    - Pap, Arthur; [with an epilogue by Brand Blanshard]. Introduction to the Philosophy of Science, An. The Free Press of Glencoe, 1962 (Box 182, Item 780)
    - Waley, Arthur. Three Ways of Thought in Ancient China. Doubleday Anchor Books, 1956 (Box 182, Item 781)
    - Hook, Sidney. From Hegel to Marx, Studies in the Intellectual Development of Karl Marx. Victor Gollancz Ltd, 1936 (Box 182, Item 782)
    - Russell, Bertrand; [edited, with an introduction by Lester E. Denonn]. Dictionary of Mind, Matter and Morals.Philosophical Library, 1952 (Box 182, Item 783)
    - Sellars, Roy Wood. Lending a Hand to Hylas. Roy Wood Sellars(?), 1968 (Box 182, Item 784)
    - Berkeley and Modern Problems, The Symposia Read at the Joint Session of The Aristotelian Society and the Mind Society at Dublin, July 10th-12th, 1953. Harrison and Sons Ltd (Box 182, Item 785)
    - Hobbes, Thomas; [with an essay by the late W.G. Pogson Smith]. Leviathan, reprinted from the edition of 1651. Oxford at the Clarendon Press, 1909 (Box 182, Item 786)
    - Sellars, R.W. Essentials of Philosophy, The. The Macmillan Company, 1917 (Box 182, Item 787)
    - Sellars, Roy Wood. Critical Realism, A Study of the Nature and Conditions of Knowledge. Rand McNally & Company, 1916 (Box 182, Item 788)
    - Sellars, R.W. Next Step in Democracy, The. The Macmillan Company, 1916 (Box 182, Item 789)
    - Sellars, Roy Wood. Evolutionary Naturalism. The Open Court Publishing Company, 1922 (Box 182, Item 790)
    - Drake, Durant, et al. Essays in Critical Realism, A Co-operative Study of the Problem of Knowledge. Macmillan and Co., Ltd, 1920 (Box 182, Item 791)
    - Sellars, Roy Wood. Evolutionary Naturalism. The Open Court Publishing Company, 1922 (Box 182, Item 792)
  - Annotated Journals, dates; 2.
    This subseries contains entire journals that feature either dedications or annotations. The journals are almost exclusively concerned with philosophical issues and are arranged alphabetically by journal title. The vast majority of the journals contain some form of annotation. However, there are a few journals that only contain a dedication or an inclusion. The dedications generally consist of a simple salutation to Sellars from the author of an article published in the journal. While a few of the inclusions appear to relate directly to an article or the entire journal, the bulk of the inclusions appear to be unrelated items that were simply used as bookmarks, or were temporarily placed in the journal and forgotten. The annotations vary greatly in substance. Some of the journals only contain one or two markings that appear to have little significance. The remaining journals tend to have one or two articles that are annotated in some fashion. These annotations may include underlined text, symbolic markings in the margins, or some written commentary. In a few instances, the journals are highly annotated. This statement is especially true with the publications The Monist and Synthese. In addition, the annotations in Philosophical Studies tend to be editorial in nature, rather than philosophical.
  - Offprints by Sellars, 1947-1982; 3.
    This subseries contains manuscripts published by Sellars between the years 1947 and 1982. The manuscripts are either offprints or reprints from the publisher and contain no unique markings such as annotations or dedications. They are arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "Abstract Entities", 1963 (Box 182, Folder 3)
    - "Abstract Entities and Classes As Abstract Entities and the Russell Paradox", 1963 (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - "Acquaintance and Description Again", 1949 (Box 182, Folder 5)
    - "Actions and Events", 1973 (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - "The Adverbial Theory of the Objects of Sensation", 1975 (Box 182, Folder 7)
    - "Are There Non-Deductive Logics?", undated (Box 182, Folder 8)
    - "Aristotelian Philosophies of Mind", c. 1949 (Box 182, Folder 9)
    - "Behaviorism, Language, and Meaning", 1980 (Box 182, Folder 10)
    - "Being and Being Known", 1960 (Box 182, Folder 11)
    - "Berkeley and Descartes: Reflections on the Theory of Ideas", 1978 (Box 182, Folder 12)
    - "Classes As Abstract Entities and the Russell Paradox", 1963 (Box 182, Folder 13)
    - "Concepts As Involving Laws and Inconceivable Without Them", 1948 (Box 182, Folder 14)
    - "Conceptual Change", undated (Box 182, Folder 15)
    - "Counterfactuals, Dispositions, and the Causal Modalities", 1957 (Box 182, Folder 16)
    - "The Double-Knowledge Approach to the Mind-Body Problem", 1971 (Box 182, Folder 17)
    - "Empiricism and Abstract Entities", c. 1963 (Box 182, Folder 18)
    - "Empiricism and the Philosophy of Mind", 1956 (Box 182, Folder 19)
    - "Epistemology and the New Way of Words", 1947 (Box 182, Folder 20)
    - "Form and Content in Ethical Theory", 1967 (Box 182, Folder 21)
    - "Foundations for a Metaphysics of Pure Process", 1981 (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - "Givenness and Explanatory Coherence", 1964 (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - "Grammar and Existence: A Preface to Ontology", 1960 (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - "Hochberg on Mapping, Meaning, and Metaphysics", 1977 (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - "The Identity Approach to the Mind-Body Problem", 1965 (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - "Imperatives, Intentions, and the Logic of Ought", 1963 (Box 183, Folder 6)
    - "Induction as Vindication", 1964 (Box 183, Folder 7)
    - "Inferencia y Significado", 1960 (Box 183, Folder 8)
    - "Inference and Meaning", 1953 (Box 183, Folder 9)
    - "Intentionality and the Mental", 1957 (Box 183, Folder 10)
    - "Intentionality, Language, and Translation", 1974 (Box 183, Folder 11)
    - "The Intentional Realism of Everett Hall", 1966 (Box 183, Folder 12)
    - "Is Scientific Realism Tenable?", 1977 (Box 183, Folder 13)
    - "Is There a Synthetic A Priori?", 1953 (Box 183, Folder 14)
    - "Kant's Transcendental Idealism", undated (Box 183, Folder 15)
    - "Kant's Views on Sensibility and Understanding", 1967 (Box 183, Folder 16)